AGUNG FIRMANSYAH

DIGITAL SPECIALIST

Tigaraksa Tangerang Banten | Firmansya15Agung09@gmail.com | +628128854459 | LinkedIn | GitHub

ABOUT

I am a Digital Specialist in Manufacturing Industry companies, and fresh graduate at Alterra academy in the field of Quality Assurance Engineer where I learned about Fundamental Quality Engineer, Automation Testing and also Manual Testing. and I am currently interested in working as a Quality Assurance Engineer Automation or Quality Assurance Engineer Manual.

SKILLS

- Java
- PHP
- JavaScript
- CSS
- HTML

- Rest Assured
- Selenium
- Appium
- Postman
- Katalon

- Trello
- Serenity BDD
- TestRial
- JMeter
- SCRUM

Jira

MySql

■ API

PROJECT

SPORT ARENA (CAPSTONE PROJECT) Alterra Academy

Sport Arena is an application designed to make it easier for users to find sports arenas, and make it easier for sports arena owners to rent out their sports facilities.

- Create 346 Test Case/Scenario API and Web.
- Create Automation Test API and WEB With Serenity BDD, Cucumber, Maven And Selenium.
- Execute Test Case Manual And Automation.
- Create Report With Selenium / Cucumber.
- Implemented SCRUM in the project.
- Implemented Trunk-Based Development in the project Github.

ANDROID AUTOMATION TESTING Alterra Academy

- Create Testcase with Gherkin Language.
- Create Automation android using Appium, Serenity BDD, Cucumber & Maven.
- Create report with Selenium / Cucumber.

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Digital Specialist

PT ADIS DIMENSION FOOTWEAR (2019 – Present)

- System analyze.
- Develop system for reporting PPH Production.
- · Involved in UAT with the IT team.
- Teaching new systems that exist in the company.

Team Leader (QMS)

PT ADIS DIMENSION FOOTWEAR (2017 – 2019)

- Responsible for product quality.
- Daily Report Rework Defect Process Shoe.
- Weekly & Monthly Report Balance Score Card (BSC).

Operator Production

PT ADIS DIMENSION FOOTWEAR (2015 – 2017)

- Sewing Process shoes
- Assembling Process shoes

COURSES AND BOOTCAMP

ALTERRA ACADEMY February 2022 - May 2022

Quality Engineer Immersive Program (Bootcamp)

- Manual Testing with TestRial Menagement Tools.
- Automation Test Web with Gherkin, Serenity BDD, Selenium and Maven.
- Automation Test API with Gherkin, Serenity BDD, Selenium, Maven, Rest Assured & Json Schema.
- Automation Test Android with Gherkin, Serenity BDD, Appium and Maven.
- Performance Testing with Jmeter.

CODEPOLITAN.COM January 2019 – December 2019

Full Stack Web Developer Training

- Front-end with Bootstrap, React, JavaScript and CSS tailwind.
- Back-end with PHP, Codelgniter, MySql.

EDUCATION

STMIK Bandung September 2015 – February 2019

Bachelor of Informatics Engineering

- Active as a member of Badan Executive Mahasiswa (BEM) Organization
- Active as a member of Mahasiswa Pecinta Alam (MAPALA) Organization
- GPA 3.49